<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:63827/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:63827/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polymorphism in Object-Oriented Programming: Concepts and Examples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Polymorphism, a core concept in Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), enables objects of different classes to be treated as objects of a common superclass. It&amp;rsquo;s a principle that enhances flexibility and modularity in software development.&#xA;Understanding Polymorphism Polymorphism allows methods to do different things based on the object it is acting upon, despite sharing the same name. This capability is crucial for implementing interface-based programming and method overriding.&#xA;Non-Technical Example Consider a simple action like &amp;lsquo;drawing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encapsulation in Object-Oriented Programming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop-encapsulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop-encapsulation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Encapsulation Encapsulation, a cornerstone of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), encapsulates data and operations on data within objects, shielding the internal state from unauthorized access. This principle enhances modularity, maintainability, and data integrity within software applications.&#xA;The Pillars of Encapsulation Encapsulation intertwines with other OOP principles like abstraction, inheritance, and polymorphism, but it stands out by offering:&#xA;Data Hiding: Restricting access to the internal state of an object. Interface Exposure: Exposing a controlled interface to interact with an object&amp;rsquo;s data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Programming: Principles and Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:63827/blogs/oop/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm based on the concept of &amp;ldquo;objects&amp;rdquo;, which can contain data and code: data in the form of fields (often known as attributes or properties), and code, in the form of procedures (often known as methods).&#xA;Core Principles of OOP OOP is built around four main principles: encapsulation, abstraction, inheritance, and polymorphism. These principles help developers create more modular, reusable, and maintainable code.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
