<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PHP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/introduction_to_php/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/introduction_to_php/</guid>
      <description>PHP: The Server-Side Scripting Language PHP, or Hypertext Preprocessor, began as a small open-source project in 1995. It&amp;rsquo;s now one of the most widely used server-side scripting languages, especially for web development. It powers everything from blogs and forums to e-commerce and social networks.&#xA;PHP by the Numbers Usage: Powers over 78% of all websites with a known server-side programming language, including major platforms like WordPress. Community: Large and active, contributing to a vast ecosystem of frameworks, libraries, and tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redux: Managing State in JavaScript Apps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/react-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/react-redux/</guid>
      <description>Redux: Simplifying State Management Redux is a predictable state container for JavaScript apps, often used with libraries like React, Angular, and Vue. It helps manage the state of an application in a single global object, making state mutations predictable through a strict contract of actions and reducers.&#xA;Why Redux? Redux provides a clear structure for managing state, making it easier to debug and test applications. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly useful in complex applications where multiple components need access to the same state.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React JS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/react-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/react-introduction/</guid>
      <description>React&amp;rsquo;s Origin Story React wasn&amp;rsquo;t born in a vacuum. It was Facebook&amp;rsquo;s answer to specific challenges: managing vast, dynamic user interfaces with data changing all the time. Before React, updating user interfaces efficiently was a major headache for developers. React&amp;rsquo;s solution? The virtual DOM, a game-changer that allowed for minimal actual DOM manipulation, leading to significant performance improvements.&#xA;The Virtual DOM Explained The virtual DOM is a lightweight copy of the real DOM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Layouts with CSS Grid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/css-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/css-grid/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to CSS Grid CSS Grid represents a paradigm shift in web layout design, offering a grid-based layout system that enhances both the simplicity and complexity of web designs. It facilitates handling rows and columns together, a significant step beyond the capabilities of Flexbox.&#xA;CSS Grid vs. Flexbox Flexbox is one-dimensional, optimal for layouts focusing on a single row or column. CSS Grid, however, operates on two dimensions, allowing developers to manage the layout across rows and columns simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
