<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Walid&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/design_patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/design_patterns/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Software design patterns are typical solutions to common problems in software design. They serve as templates for solving recurring design issues, promoting more efficient and effective development practices. This guide focuses on JavaScript and PHP examples to explore significant design patterns.&#xA;Creational Patterns Creational patterns provide mechanisms for object creation, increasing flexibility and reuse of existing code.&#xA;Factory Method in JavaScript The Factory Method pattern defines an interface for creating an object, letting subclasses alter the type of objects that will be created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness and Meditation for Programmers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/mindfulness-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 08:44:10 +0733</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/mindfulness-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the fast-paced world of software development, maintaining mental well-being can often be overlooked. Amidst challenging deadlines and complex problems, programmers can benefit from the practices of mindfulness and meditation.&#xA;What is Mindfulness and Meditation? Mindfulness involves being present and fully engaged with the current moment, without distraction or judgment. Meditation, a technique for achieving mindfulness, can involve focusing on the breath or a specific thought to gain mental clarity and emotional calmness.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
